Revenge is beautiful.
Colombiana is a action, thriller, crime film directed by Olivier Megaton.
After witnessing her parents’ murder as a child in Bogota,
Cataleya Restrepo grows up to be a stone-cold assassin.
She works for her uncle as a hitman by day, but her personal time is spent engaging in vigilante murders that
she hopes will lead her to her ultimate target: the mobster responsible for her parents' death.
Cataleya Restrepo, played by Zoe Saldaña.
Emilio, played by Cliff Curtis.
Richard, played by Callum Blue.
Danny Delanay, played by Michael Vartan.
Special Agent Ross, played by Lennie James.
Cataleya Restrepo (Age10), played by Amandla Stenberg.
Colombiana is a 2011 French English-language action thriller film co-written
and produced by Luc Besson and directed by Olivier Megaton.
The film stars Zoe Saldaña with supporting roles by Michael Vartan,
Cliff Curtis, Lennie James, Callum Blue, and Jordi Mollà.
The film is about Cataleya, a nine-year-old girl in
Colombia whose family is killed by a drug lord.
Fifteen years later, a grown Cataleya seeks her revenge.
The film had a generally unfavorable reception from critics, but
Saldaña's performance and action sequences were praised.
It grossed $63.4 million against a $40 million production budget.
The film explores themes of street gang, uncle,
female assassin, witness to murder.
The tone is emotional and intense.